DR ALEX KIRKUP

Data Analyst

About

Email: alex.kirkup@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-kirkup **GitHub**: https://alex-kirkup.github.io/portfolio/

Medium: https://medium.com/@alex.kirkup

I have been Lead Data Analyst at a thriving secondary school in Fareham, Hampshire since 2019, where I have transformed the culture of learning and improved outcomes for pupils, parents and teachers using pupil data. I have a strong skillset in data analytics, statistics and coding with Python and I am looking to move to a full-time role in data analysis. See my GitHub Page for more information: https://alex-kirkup.github.io/portfolio/

Skills

3+ years

Python	SQL	Excel	PowerBI	Statistics
Django / FastAPI	SQL Server	Xlwings (Python)	Visualisations	Teaching
Pandas	MySQL	PivotTables	Dashboards	Modelling
NumPy	PostgreSQL	PowerQuery	DAX	PhD studies
Matplotlib	3+ years	VBA	1 year	10+ years
AGILF / Git / Pylint		10+ years		

Relevant Experience

Lead Data Analyst, Cams Hill School, 06/2019-present

- Created and implemented a new whole school approach to working with pupil data by automating Excel, incorporating new visualisations, modelling and data collection, which has improved the outcomes of interventions and significantly reduced staff workload.
- Modelled GCSE grades assigned to pupils based on individual, school and national past attainment during Covid disruption to exams.
- Currently transitioning the school's data architecture and visualizations to a Python full-stack solution with a Django/PostgreSQL backend and HTML/HTMX/Javascript frontend

Pupil Premium Coordinator, Cams Hill School, 06/2017-06/2019

- Created a system of deprivation indexing which continues to enable teachers to work with disadvantaged pupils more effectively.
- Introduced the annual Pupil Premium Review which assesses the impact of all interventions
 with this group and the effectiveness of spending. Expanded this as a process to manage
 and monitor all interventions across the school.

Teacher of Mathematics, Cams Hill School, 09/2015-present

- Introduced a new system of individualised pupil feedback in mathematics by automating Excel which has changed the culture of learning for pupils and improved outcomes, created new positive links between home and school, and increased teachers' capacity to plan effectively.
- Created the Mixed Question Worksheet Generator based on a bank of 10,000 pre-made questions to match the department's teaching to the latest education research.

Teacher of Mathematics, The Hayling College, 09/2013-08/2015

Research Fellow, Department of Politics and International Relations, University of Sheffield, 09/2010-08/2012

University Lecturer, Department of Politics and International Relations, University of Sheffield, 09/2009-08/2010

Teaching Fellow, Department of Politics and International Relations, University of Southampton, 09/2008-08/2009

References

Mrs Gwennan Harrison-Jones Headteacher Cams Hill School Fareham Hampshire, PO15 6NL office@camshill.com Mr Charles Fairhead Head of Mathematics Cams Hill School Fareham Hampshire, PO15 6NL office@camshill.com

Education

PGCE Secondary Education

University of Portsmouth, 2012-2013

PhD Global Political Economy

(Including MPhil Statistical and Research Methods)

University of Southampton, 2005-2009

MSc Global Politics

University of Southampton, 2004-2005

BSc (Hons) Economics and Politics

University of Southampton, 2001-2004

A-Levels Mathematics, Further Mathematics (AS), Computing, Business Studies

Fareham College, 1999-2001

About me

In four of my publications:

- The First Millennium Development Goal: In the Hands of the Market, Kavilando 1(1)
- Securitization, Conditionality, Accountability: Building Our Common Future? International Public Policy Review 6 (1)
- Globalization and Human Rights (with Tony Evans), in The International Studies Encyclopedia, Oxford: ISA/Wiley-Blackwell
- Liberal Silences and the Political Economy of Global Governance, Political Studies Review 6(1)

In four books I am reading now:

- Machine Learning with Python, Sarah Guido & Andreas Mueller
- Think Bayes, Allen B. Downey
- Eight Feet in the Andes, Dervla Murphy
- Foundation, Isaac Asimov